Panagiotis Adamopoulos

Delivery Manager - Principal Software Architect

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name:Panagiotis AdamopoulosDate of birth:02 / 03 / 1980Marital Status:MarriedMilitary Services:FulfilledAddress:9 Agias Sofias Street, PC. 17123, Athens, GreecePhone:210 933 4108, 215 555 6984Mobile:6934786024, 6907720674Email:panagiotis.adamopoulos@gmail.com		
Marital Status:MarriedMilitary Services:FulfilledAddress:9 Agias Sofias Street, PC. 17123, Athens, GreecePhone:210 933 4108, 215 555 6984Mobile:6934786024, 6907720674	Name:	Panagiotis Adamopoulos
Military Services: Fulfilled Address: 9 Agias Sofias Street, PC. 17123, Athens, Greece Phone: 210 933 4108, 215 555 6984 Mobile: 6934786024, 6907720674	Date of birth:	02 / 03 / 1980
Address: 9 Agias Sofias Street, PC. 17123, Athens, Greece Phone: 210 933 4108, 215 555 6984 Mobile: 6934786024, 6907720674	Marital Status:	Married
Phone: 210 933 4108, 215 555 6984 Mobile: 6934786024, 6907720674	Military Services:	Fulfilled
Mobile: 6934786024, 6907720674	Address:	9 Agias Sofias Street, PC. 17123, Athens, Greece
	Phone:	210 933 4108, 215 555 6984
Email: panagiotis.adamopoulos@gmail.com	Mobile:	6934786024, 6907720674
	Email:	panagiotis.adamopoulos@gmail.com

PROFESIONAL PROFILE

A results-driven, highly adaptable in quickly changing technical environments and with strong managerial skills, Delivery Manager.

Strong in taking quick decisions and plan solutions to complicated problems. Expert in communication with partners and clients.

Expert in JEE, Spring, Angular, React, Oracle JET, Typescript, PHP MVC, Symfony MVC, Drupal, Liferay, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL with database analysis and design.

Strong experience in specification analysis and user documentation of complex software projects. Experience in DevOps Tasks and server administration.

Many years of management experience in IT environments and in leading large teams.

Very Experienced in:

- Managing project requirements, budgets, KPIs, etc.
- Engineering large-scale applications from database to services to user interfaces.
- Engineering web-based and cross-platform applications.
- Managing and supporting multiple projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dixons South East Europe

Delivery Manager & Tribe Lead

2023 - Now

Delivery Manager in Commerce Sector and Commerce Tribe Lead.

- Technical Leading of all development resources of the organization and external resources.
- Promote Agile principles in the Scrum teams and stakeholders and drive process improvements.
- Participate and share knowledge as well as promote best practices.
- Design, track, and report on success criteria and KPIs for each project ().
- Design Delivery Roadmaps, follow up on implementation, identify and mitigate risks.
- Managing project requirements, budgets, KPIs, etc.

Netcompany - Intrasoft

2019 - 2023

Principal Enterprise Architect

Principal Enterprise Architect and Technical Lead in Software & Product Development Department

- Principal Architect & Technical Lead in Netcompany Products Sector in React and Spring Framework, using microservices architecture.
- Principal Architect & Technical Lead in Enterprise banking applications in Angular, C# using microservices and micro frontends.
- Principal Architect & Technical Lead in Enterprise banking applications in React, Spring Framework using microservices and micro frontends.
- Solution Architect in Enterprise Airlines Applications using Python (Flask & Django Frameworks) and Drupal
- Solution Architect in Enterprise Health Insurance Applications in JEE, Oracle Fusion Middleware and OracleJET.

UniSystems SA

2016 - 2019

Solutions Architect

Solutions Architect in International Business Unit / SW Technical Division.

- Architecture and Development of software applications with JEE, Angular and Typescript.
- Architecture and Development of web applications with Spring MVC, Drupal and AngularJS

Mega Channel – Tiletipos SA

2015 - 2016

Solutions Architect

Solutions Architect in the development of web, mobile and desktop software applications. Most of the web applications developed using Java's Spring Framework, Drupal and Python based CMS, using restful web services.

- Development of software applications with JEE, Spring Framework and Python with MSSQL Server and PostgreSQL using NLB Cluster and Microsoft high availability and failover Technologies
- Development of Video automation applications using Spring Framework
- Development of custom Drupal intranet and mobile applications.

Solutions Architect

2012 - 2015

DNA Creative Group LTD

Solutions Architect in the development of web, mobile and desktop software applications, using JEE, Spring Framework, Symfony Framework and Drupal.

- Specification Analysis in the development of medical software based on JEE and PostgreSQL
- Development of decoupled solutions and mobile applications using Drupal and Symfony Framework as backend and Ionic Framework as the frontend implementation.

Lead Software Engineer

2009 - 2012

DNA Creative Group LTD

Lead Developer in the development of web, mobile and desktop software applications. Most of the web applications developed using JEE, Spring, Drupal, or custom PHP based CMS.

- Development of web based software using Spring Framework and JEE.
- Development of web based software and mobile applications using Drupal and Symfony Framework as backend and Ionic Framework as the frontend implementation.

Research and Development Engineer

2009

Druckfarben Hellas SA

Chemical engineer in the department of new low-VOC water and oil colors and tints for Greece and Romania.

- Water and oil colors quality control.
- Development of the new Kraft Paints color palette
- Client support in the field of tinting problems in large scale construction projects.

Senior Construction Engineer

2008 - 2009

AP SA

Chemical Engineer and Safety Engineer in the department of construction projects for Greek and International Petroleum Industry.

- Lead engineer in construction projects at Hellenic Petroleum, refineries of Aspropyrgos and Elefsina,
 Greece
- Lead engineer in construction projects at Motoroil Hellas, refineries of Korinthos, Greece
- Lead engineer in maintenance projects of liquid and gas fuel tanks in Agioi Theodoroi, Greece

Analyst

2007 - 2008

Hellenic Airforce

Chemical Engineer in the quality control department of the Hellenic Airforce Laboratory.

- Quality control of gas, oil, grease and hydraulic fluids of airplanes, helicopters and special operational vehicles.
- Quality control of breathing oxygen in fighter airplanes.
- Research and Development in phasmatoscopic oil analysis of special helicopters and operational vehicles

Ippokrates College

2002 - 2004

Teacher

Microsoft Office and Web Design teacher in Ippokrates College, Patra, Greece.

- ECDL Core and ECDL Advanced
- Microsoft Office Specialist
- Cambridge International Examination
- Adobe Photoshop for graphic designers
- Web Design Level A: Microsoft FrontPage and Adobe Dreamweaver
- Web Design Level B: Creating dynamic websites using ASP.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, JEE, Spring, Python, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, SASS, XML, Typescript, Twig, Blade, Smarty

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Redis

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOSX

Frameworks: Spring, Vaadin, Symfony, Codeigniter, Flask, Django, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Angular, OracleJET, React, NativeScript, 960GS, Omega, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, Ionic, Cordova

CMS: Drupal, Liferay, dotCMS, Alfresco Digital Business Platform

Servers: Debian, Ubuntu, Red Hat, CentOS

Application Servers: IIS, Wildfly, Apache, NGINX, WebSphere, Oracle WebLogic

Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, AdobeXD

Microsoft Office Suites: MS Office (ECDL Certification), LibreOffice

Additional Software Skills: Sparx Enterprise Architect, PowerDesigner, JasperReports, JMS, Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, Hazelcast, SonarQube, SIG, JUnit, Mockito, Flyway scripts

CERTIFICATIONS

Drupal Certified Developer by Acquia

Certified SysAdmin, by Linux Foundation

Building a Basic Site Using Drupal 8

Extending and Managing a Drupal 8 Site

Certified Python Developer

Certified Web Developer

Certified AngulaJS Developer

Prestashop Frontend Developer

Prestashop Backend Developer

Serverless Architecture

Cloud Architecture, advanced concepts

Agile Marketing Foundations

VOLUNTEER WORK

Prestashop Ambassador

DrupalCon North America Committee Member

Drupal Association Member

Oracle Jet Greek Community Administrator

Vaadin Flow Contributor

COURSES

Oracle Data Warehousing και Oracle BI

VMWare Core Spring Training		
Drupalize Acquia Certified Developer Training		
Linux Foundation SysAdmin Training		
Linux Virtualization Using KVM		
Accelerate large-scale Java Application migrations and reduce time, cost and risk, Red Hat		
Security-enhanced Linux for mere mortals by Thomas Cameron - Global Solutions Architect Leader, Red Hat		
Using Yum Repositories to Streamline Package Deployment in Linux Environments		
Deploying Virtual Hosts in Linux, Derek Carter		
Bad Packets for the Bad Guys. Training in web security		
Accenture Intelligent Orchestration Platform—a holistic management approach		
Adobe Experience Manager ("CQ"): CMS Editors Training		
Best Practice Site Architecture in Drupal 8! How to make the right decisions for you development plan		
Couch Coding: Drupal Performance		
Linux Performance Analysis With Perf, Dominic Duval, Enterprise Training Director, The Linux Foundation		
Multi-Site High-Availability Clusters, Florian Haas, The Linux Foundation		
Oracle MySQL Cloud Service Propel Innovation and Time-to-Market		
Java 8 Web services		
Ionic 4 Training		
Scrum Training		

EDUCATION

University of Patra, Department of Chemical Engineering Diploma in Chemical Engineering	1998 - 2005
National Technical University of Athens MSc in Materials Science, Chemical Engineering Department	2005 - 2007
University Of Piraeus MSc in Informatics, Department of Computer Science	2014 - 2016

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Mother Tongue: Greek

Foreign Languages: English (Certificate of Proficiency in English, University of Cambridge, Michigan University)

Spanish (Diploma Intermedio)

PUBLICATIONS - BOOKS

Design and Development of a Learning Management System for Vocational Education

Vocational Education and Training Apprenticeship: Using Teaching and Learning Analytics in a Learning Management System for improved Collaboration, Individual Empowerment and Development of Apprentices

Integration of Machine Learning in Advanced Learning Management Systems

Study, design and development of a modern video system to improve services from production to the end user

Web-based services to support the Vocational Education and Training Apprenticeship

Symfony Framework 3, A developer's guide, Desmos Publications

Attacking Drupal - Understanding Web Security

Security Based Linux, a custom linux distro based on openSUSE that aims to be an alternative to Kali Linux

Mailguard Server, a custom linux distro based on openSUSE that is used as an email antispam solution

A case study of using Linux in the Municipality of Munich, Germany, Linux Format Magazine, February 1, 2012

Development and deployment of .NET Applications in Linux, Linux Format Magazine, April 1, 2012

Conductive polymers of pyrrole and their applications

Magnetic Materials for Data Recording - Magnetic Recording using colossal magnetoresistance

New Production processes of tissue papers (Elite and Delica Industries)

Interfacial phenomena in ultrathin nickel films over yttria-stabilized zirconia

Ion implantation of nitrogen for surface hardening of steel

Spectroscopic aircraft oil analysis manual. (Technical manual of Hellenic Airforce Academy)

Aerosol effect on Earth's climate

SEMINARS

Best Practices for Creating Responsive Websites

Google marketing for web developers

Minimum Viable Product: Get Your Site From Concept to Market with Open Source

Accelerating Digital Site Creation for Marketers How to Improve Your Digital Governance How to Migrate from.NET to Drupal Improving Website Performance and Scalability with Memcached The Practical Guide to Selecting a New CMS for Technology Companies Cloud Automation Best Practices Using API, Drush, Command-Line and Scripting Microsoft® Partner Event - Client optimization & Business Productivity Platform & Cloud Power, Microsoft Hellas Server Roadshow 2010, Microsoft Hellas Specification Analysis for ISO 9001:2000 Google marketing for web developers Magnetic materials for sensor construction Quality control of raw materials and products in materials industries Economic activities of Greece in the Balkans and Turkey, as a factor shaping foreign policy and economic diplomacy Allotropic forms of carbon Applied Magneto elasticity Company management and Logistics Plastics - Polymers: their applications and their effect on our lives **Biomaterials** Thermoplastic polymers and their applications

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Contribution to the open source community

Smart buildings and Smart Vehicles using open source solutions

Columnist for various publications and magazines (Linux Format Greece, Linux Inside)

Ways of migrating different technologies to different environments for the creation of cross platform software

Guitar Playing